CURRICULLLUM VITAE

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : DR OLIVIA TAN YEN PING

Current Designation : PRINCIPAL ASSISTANT DIRECTOR
Department : CLINICAL SUPPORT SERVICES UNIT

MEDICAL DEVELOPMENT DIVISION
MINISTRY OF HEALTH MALAYSIA

Date of Birth : 10TH MAY 1984

Place of Birth : KUCHING
Nationality : MALAYSIAN
Tel (Mobile) : 60168092611

Email : OLIVIATYP@GMAIL.COM

Address (Home) : 2A, JALAN SB INDAH 2/10

JALAN SB INDAH,

SERI KEMBANGAN, 43300

SELANGOR

Marital Status : MARRIED

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Doctor of Medicine (MD), Russian State Medical University (RSMU), Moscow

Masters in International Health Services and Hospital Management

2017

PROFESSIONAL LICENSE

Registered with Malaysian Medical Council (Registration Number : 50361) as medical practitioner in Malaysia

CAREER HISTORY

Sarawak General Hospital House Office(Intern) 2008 – 2010
Sarawak General Hospital Medical Officer 2010 - 2011
Kuala Lumpur Hospital Medical Officer 2011 - 2014
Medical Development Division Principal Assistant Director 2014 - present

COMPUTER SKILLS

Good with Microsoft Office (Pitman Qualification)

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I have work in Malaysia's healthcare system for the past seven years. I have work for up to 6 years in the clinical side (internship - 2 years, emergency department medical officer -4 months, Obstetric and Gynecology Department − 3 ½ years) as a junior doctor before I made a career move to go to the administrative side since May 2014 . I am working in the Clinical Support Services Unit in the Medical Development Division for the past one year. Basically, the unit is in charge of making sure that all the services provided by the Public Hospitals in Malaysia is functioning according to the policy that is made by our side. Our division will come up with a renewed and updated policy every five years for all the services provided in our public hospital. New guidelines and protocol will be set up whenever there is a need in the services. I enjoyed doing what I am doing currently I furthered my education to do MSc in International Health Services and Hospital Management to further strengthen my knowledge on management. By doing this Masters, I am able to look at all the healthcare system practiced across the world and I would like to adapt all the good management skills practiced in the healthcare sector by other countries and bring it to my home country to further strengthen our healthcare system. I would like to share my knowledge of the healthcare system in my countries with others so there is a transfer of knowledge and in that way, we will all learn from the good points and avoid the bad point in the healthcare system. I hope to make Malaysia's Healthcare System to be one of the best in the world one day and easily assessable by the public regardless of race or status to create a better quality of life for every single person in Malaysia.